[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a860", "question": "Belgium's name is derived from what Roman province?", "answer": "Gallia Belgica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f29", "question": "Which band member of The Sex Pistols died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Sid Vicious", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21d", "question": "What city was Martin Luther King, Jr. killed in?", "answer": "Memphis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339669", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which breed of dog is Santa's Little Helper?", "answer": "Greyhound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66f6b52a821ff76ae8b1f", "question": "In Tennessee, it\u2019s illegal to hold office if you\u2019ve done what?", "answer": "Fought in a duel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339065", "question": "What does the Latin word \"Verbatim\" translate into?", "answer": "Word for word", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ae", "question": "In the B&O Railroad, what does B&O stand for?", "answer": "Baltimore and Ohio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f1683df7c52aae91cc07c4", "question": "What is the fear of light flashes known as?", "answer": "Selaphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b320", "question": "Who became prime minister of Cuba in 1959?\u00a0", "answer": "Fidel Castro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f3", "question": "What 1970 movie revolves around a cat named Duchess, her three kittens, and an evil butler named Edgar?", "answer": "The Aristocats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ad3e01dd7bf43be5e778", "question": "Which Crayola color was named by a five-year-old?", "answer": "Razzmatazz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfbaa8003d27d341092bc4", "question": "What are Easter Island's famous statues called?", "answer": "Moai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c316877e98cb9777898f", "question": "Which country has the largest territorial claim in Antarctica?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e8", "question": "In which European city can you find the \"Mouth of Truth\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c801", "question": "What invisible \"color\" can bees see on flower petals?", "answer": "Ultraviolet, or Bee purple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ba", "question": "The zodiac sign \"Leo\" refers to what animal?", "answer": "The lion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b371", "question": "In World War II, where was the defensive line known as the \"Gin Drinkers Line\"?", "answer": "Hong Kong", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa5", "question": "What superhero built a \"Fortress of Solitude\" at the North Pole?", "answer": "Superman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef65b56ce05a3942286e70", "question": "Who is the Winslow family\u2019s nerdy neighbor in \"Family Matters\"", "answer": "Steve Urkel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339789", "question": "What two characters from \"The Little Rascals\" are named after plants?", "answer": "Alfalfa and Buckwheat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec23ce8dc25ca9e12ef633", "question": "What don't the children need in Pink Floyd's \"Another Brick In The Wall\"?", "answer": "An education", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3235f5bf195a31e15d73b4", "question": "Who played the electric piano on the Beatles track \"Get Back\"?", "answer": "Billy Preston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a207", "question": "Harvey Lee Yeary became famous under what name?", "answer": "Lee Majors", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c1", "question": "Who directed the 1951 film \"An American in Paris\"?", "answer": "Vincente Minnelli\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51b04ff04d658268c930b", "question": "What kind of man-eating monster did Odysseus blind?", "answer": "Cyclops", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fe", "question": "What kind of poisoning is known as plumbism?", "answer": "Lead poisoning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f72", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Humbert Humbert?", "answer": "Melmoth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c755", "question": "What is the opposite of insulin and secreted by the pancreas?", "answer": "Glucagon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cefc060948005ec986edcda", "question": "Who is the first member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Heejin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febbc737e83c707845b214c", "question": "Which band's debut album was entitled \"Appetite for Destruction\"?", "answer": "Guns N' Roses'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a992", "question": "What river flows through Jackson Hole, Wyoming?", "answer": "The Snake River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa2", "question": "What are wrapped in bacon to make the dish \"Angels on Horseback\"?", "answer": "Oysters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e3", "question": "What \u201cStar Trek\u201d character had a name meaning \u201cfreedom\u201d in Swahili?", "answer": "Uhura", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bbf", "question": "What name was given to the 12 sons of Ge and Uranus?", "answer": "Titans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918e", "question": "Who is smarter than the average bear?", "answer": "Yogi Bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0d", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Quickening\"?", "answer": "Highlander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e8", "question": "What island nation was invaded by US troops in October 1983?", "answer": "Grenada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338910", "question": "Which nursery rhyme character \"kissed the girls and made them cry\"?", "answer": "Georgie Porgie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad18", "question": "Which female appeared on the 1999 US dollar coin?", "answer": "Susan B. Anthony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc0c7a469bb8041d07a051", "question": "What is \"Ajiaco\"?", "answer": "A type of chicken soup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e3", "question": "Who is the author of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" novel series?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c2f", "question": "Who voiced Snow White in the 1937 movie \"Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs\"?", "answer": "Adriana Caselotti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5bef6ce05a3942286e1b", "question": "Who directed the film \"Hacksaw Ridge\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8cd", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Yangtze river?", "answer": "China", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173d4a44491cbd7c5a17ad", "question": "Who is widely credited as the first man to reach the South Pole?", "answer": "Roald Amundsen and his crew of Norwegian explorers first reached the South Pole on December 14, 1911.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133966a", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which character has a pacemaker?", "answer": "Krusty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cb9d877e98cb97778a1d", "question": "In what country would you find Mont-Saint-Michel?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea4072ff048f679a45ab68", "question": "By what name is a quasi-stellar radio source better known?", "answer": "Quasar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339865", "question": "In Disney's \"Pinocchio\", what animal does Pinocchio get trapped inside?", "answer": "A whale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f7", "question": "What gender are whiptail lizards?", "answer": "Female", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ec725ce57c9fcac0ce71980", "question": "What grows in the brain when doing cognitive exercises?", "answer": "Dendrites", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f3a", "question": "What 1969 bestseller begins with a satellite called SCOOP crashing in Arizona?", "answer": "The Andromeda Strain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02d", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", Stewie took captive the cast of which hit TV show?", "answer": "Star Trek: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea40f3ff048f679a45ab6c", "question": "Who discovered that a moving magnet generates electric current known as electromagnetic induction?", "answer": "Michael Faraday", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d1", "question": "Which is the only independent state smaller than Monaco?", "answer": "The Vatican", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cd610e347d002c297e4ba", "question": "On what date is The Melbourne Cup traditionally held?", "answer": "The first Tuesday of November", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339329", "question": "In \"The Godfather\", who plays Michael Corleone?", "answer": "Al Pacino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6fe", "question": "What decade was Girl Scouts of America formed in?", "answer": "1910s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f3", "question": "Which famous Jazz club is the subject of a 1984 Francis Ford Coppola film?", "answer": "The Cotton Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c029", "question": "What sport is sometimes called rugger?", "answer": "Rugby union", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f47", "question": "What is the real first name of Tyler Perry's famous character, Madea?", "answer": "Mabe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df6", "question": "What album spent a record 741 weeks on Billboard's Top 200 Albums chart?", "answer": "Dark Side of the Moon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c14b", "question": "Who caused the collapse of Barings Bank and inspired the film \"Rogue Trader\"?", "answer": "Nick Leeson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c0", "question": "In kilograms, what is the weight of 1 liter of water?", "answer": "1 kg", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e93d17ccba3ffe45786ca", "question": "What was Buddy Holly's real first name?", "answer": "Charles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b65", "question": "How many of the seven dwarfs have beards?", "answer": "6", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "591c3631815febcc896f9265", "question": "Which actor took the male lead in Hitchcock's film \"The Birds\"?", "answer": "Rod Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c1", "question": "For what occassion did George Frideric Handel compose the anthem \"Zadok the Priest\"?", "answer": "Coronation of King George II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c90cfc152800b05cac20f0b", "question": "What is the only African nation with Spanish as the official language?", "answer": "Equatorial Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b2", "question": "What boxer was nicknamed the Boston Strong Boy?", "answer": "John L. Sullivan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc9", "question": "What can a lycanthrope do ?", "answer": "Change into a wolf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81b", "question": "In what part of the body would you find cowper's fluid?", "answer": "The penis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dfd", "question": "What \"Suddenly Susan\" actor ended up committing suicide?", "answer": "David Strickland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8beeec223966ae8f8845", "question": "The protagonist in \"Grand Theft Auto: Vice City\" was voiced by which actor?", "answer": "Ray Liotta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390bb", "question": "Which English author created Inspector Morse?", "answer": "Colin Dexter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398da", "question": "What TV series starred trail hands Gil Favor and Rowdy Yates?", "answer": "Rawhide", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a162b58f01ec323f8491728", "question": "Billy Joel gave a lengthy list of 20th Century events in which song?", "answer": "We Didn't Start the Fire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feccaecec223966ae8f889c", "question": "How many pounds of food does Hollywood superstar Dwayne \"the Rock\" Johnson consume daily?", "answer": "The Rock is well known to consume 10 pounds of food daily and accordingly travels with a 40,000-pound personal gym set!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a09f", "question": "Who played George Costanza on the TV show \"Seinfeld'?", "answer": "Jason Alexander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be8f", "question": "Who was knocked out in 1974 by the \"rope-a-dope\" method?", "answer": "George Forman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc48", "question": "Who was Andre Agassi's greatest tennis rival in the 1990s?", "answer": "Pete Sampras", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febae847e83c707845b20f6", "question": "Which insect uses the Milky Way to navigate?", "answer": "African dung beetle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae9270574a5ce6b56b822d", "question": "What instrument in an automobile measures distance travelled?", "answer": "Odometer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede4316ce05a3942286dd9", "question": "Parts of the movie \"Lara Croft: Tomb Raider\" were shot in what African country?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a140", "question": "In what film does Steve McQueen get to race a Mustang round the streets of San Francisco?", "answer": "Bullitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e44", "question": "What American TV actor plays himself as a fallen angel in Wim Wenders' \"Wings of Desire\"?", "answer": "Peter Falk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb2853c9bff04efae6d74f", "question": "The song \"Son of My Father\" is credited as being the first number 1 UK hit to feature which instument?", "answer": "A synthesizer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338881", "question": "What adventure tale introduced: \"Yo-ho-ho, and a bottle of rum!\"", "answer": "Treasure Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d6", "question": "What required five separate space walks to get repaired, in 1993?", "answer": "Hubble Space Telescope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a8", "question": "What U.S. state gave the world Little Richard, Otis Redding and Gladys Knight?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b2124fda37788a9a1db7", "question": "Armagnac is a brandy originating from which area of France?", "answer": "Gascony", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d998b08b8581f80b092b5", "question": "What phone did Android co-creator Andy Rubin, design and unveil in May, 2017?", "answer": "The Essential Phone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a06", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the band Soundgarden?", "answer": "Chris Cornell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c99", "question": "Who was the Roman god of the sea?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e3f5d35cb9e8bda682136b", "question": "Samuel Miller patented the first steam-powered what in 1806?", "answer": "Drill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133956d", "question": "Which cowboy musical artist first recorded the song, Here Comes Santa Claus?", "answer": "Gene Autry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ecae4a7790ded87bb38fd8c", "question": "Who was the leading goalscorer for SKC in 2012?", "answer": "Kei Kamara", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7e09ff048f679a45ac06", "question": "Ataxophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Disorder or untidiness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f4", "question": "Who is Tippi Hedren's daughter?", "answer": "Melanie Griffith", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdd19ec223966ae8f88fe", "question": "Which tennis player had the nickname \"The Rocket\"?", "answer": "Rod Laver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb50", "question": "What does the abbreviation ROI stand for in the financial world?", "answer": "Return on Investment", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a899d9d60d398dc9cf7a6ad", "question": "What US Secretary of State received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973?", "answer": "Henry Kissinger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5971dd8e89261e916c8e099e", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1990\u2019s TV show \"Grace Under Fire\"?", "answer": "Brett Butler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e68", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Yogi Bear?", "answer": "Daws Butler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339587", "question": "What movie earned Steven Spielberg his first Oscar?", "answer": "Schindler's List", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee9", "question": "What is the technical difference between rowing and sculling?", "answer": "Rowing means using a single oar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66959a5bfecdd737e087a", "question": "Who was the last king of Troy in Greek mythology?", "answer": "Priam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af9c", "question": "New Mexico, California and which other state did the US gain after the Mexican War?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ec", "question": "Which actor played the role of Edward Scissorhands?", "answer": "Johnny Depp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c894", "question": "What does the Scoville scale measure?", "answer": "Chili pepper hotness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906d", "question": "In which of Charles Dickens' novels would you find the character Dora Spenlow?", "answer": "David Copperfield", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a9", "question": "What popular brand of soup was introduced in 1897?", "answer": "Campbell's Soup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb5", "question": "What was the better-known name of Margareta Zelle, exotic dancer?", "answer": "Mata Hari", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd24", "question": "What's the official title of the chief electrician on a movie set?", "answer": "Gaffer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace3", "question": "Who was already the husband of Octavia Minor when he married Cleopatra?", "answer": "Mark Antony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b189", "question": "Who was the 40th President of the United States?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb63c7e83c707845b2125", "question": "What is a hybrid of a cow and bison called?", "answer": "Beefalo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef0", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Willy Loman?", "answer": "Death of a Salesman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067aeaff9c0647b50a805d", "question": "EgyptAir Flight 804 was en route to which city when it crashed on May 19, 2016?", "answer": "Cairo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b12a", "question": "Who did Idi Amin succeed as president of Uganda?", "answer": "Milton Obote", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c872", "question": "What piece of technology did IBM develop in 1973 that they nicknamed Winchester?", "answer": "A disk drive", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a970b61d1b4d384d5d67f", "question": "Which Disney film marked Donald Duck's debut?", "answer": "The Wise Little Hen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de4", "question": "In the TV show \"Twin Peaks\", what letter was found under Laura Palmer's fingernail?", "answer": "R", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf3", "question": "What supermodel was engaged to U2\u2019s bass guitarist Adam Clayton during the 1990\u2019s?", "answer": "Naomi Campbell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe939bf6bd93ce3a4e5f690", "question": "What term describes the hazy-looking patch surrounding the nucleus of a comet?", "answer": "Coma", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f0", "question": "What city, located at the head of the Niagara River, is the seat of New York's Erie County?", "answer": "Buffalo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf27", "question": "From which country did the dance, \"The Quadrille\", originate?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339960", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Groundskeeper Willie comes from what country?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f1d", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both John Cusack and Edward Norton?", "answer": "Nelson Rockefeller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2e", "question": "What former professional athlete was actress Halle Berry's first husband?", "answer": "David Justice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f9", "question": "In the 1986 movie \"Labyrinth\", what disguise does the King of the Goblins visits Sarah's house under?", "answer": "An owl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0af", "question": "What does an anthrophage practice?", "answer": "Cannibalism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7464a9e54d890926f6f6", "question": "How many steps must visitors take to reach the site of two Buddhist temples in China called Fanjingshan?", "answer": "8,888", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b4ebe662d71a53650ff2", "question": "What educational institution was Edgar Allen Poe thrown out of?", "answer": "West Point Military Academy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a4fe20565ad31a57c7c5", "question": "Who was the first sitting US President to throw the first pitch on Opening Day?", "answer": "William Howard Taft", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338888", "question": "What painter popularized soup cans and Brillo soap pad boxes?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4b40d06d333868d34d6df", "question": "What part of the world did the Vikings come from?", "answer": "Scandinavia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea45b7ff048f679a45ab97", "question": "How many joules make one calorie?", "answer": "4.184", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f6", "question": "What American was named captain of the Montreal Canadiens in Sep 2015?", "answer": "Max Pacioretty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339288", "question": "In the movie \"The Hunger Games\", what is Thresh's weapon of choice?", "answer": "A Scimitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339189", "question": "What organization do the FLash, Wonder Woman, Superman, Batman and the Green Lantern all belong to?", "answer": "The Justice League of America", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071c5e3745b36be73039cb", "question": "What is the name of Tony Chu\u2019s daughter in the \"Chew\" comics series?", "answer": "Olive Chu", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049db2cf93664eb10486b0", "question": "Who met in groups of 13, also called covens?", "answer": "Witches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3b", "question": "What was the occupation of James Woods' character on the TV show \"Shark\"?", "answer": "Lawyer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029f7ecad1ec93f27df760", "question": "What fruits are fermented to make Perry?", "answer": "Pears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339339", "question": "What actress played the role of Pamela Barnes Ewing on the TV show \"Dallas\"?", "answer": "Victoria Principal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cb5e877e98cb97778a18", "question": "In what year was the former republic of Czechoslovakia formed?", "answer": "1918", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339154", "question": "In \"The Saint\" series of books, what is Inspector Teal's full name?", "answer": "Claud Eustace Teal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b476", "question": "What year saw the founding of the Michelin tire company?", "answer": "1889", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb2", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Tom Collins?", "answer": "Lemon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc4f76ce05a3942286f39", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Girls Just Want to Have Fun\"?", "answer": "Cyndi Lauper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a61f", "question": "What lake is located several miles west of Carson City?", "answer": "Lake Tahoe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8c23ec223966ae8f8846", "question": "In 2000, which artist(s) tied Michael Jackson's 1984 record of winning eight Grammys in a single year?", "answer": "Santana (won eight Grammy Awards in 2000, tying the record set by Michael Jackson)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3cd", "question": "What country is sometimes called the Land of Fire and Ice?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339677", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Springfield's music store?", "answer": "King Toot's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f7", "question": "In science, what does a skull and bones represent?", "answer": "Toxic chemical", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e93567ccba3ffe45786c5", "question": "What word is used to describe \"bell shaped flowers\"?", "answer": "Campanulate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a13e", "question": "What actress wrote the autobiography \"Call Me Anna\"?", "answer": "Patty Duke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a69a", "question": "Toledo Bend Reservoir is a man-made lake located between what two US states?", "answer": "Louisiana and Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133895a", "question": "What musical is based on the book \"Anna and the King of Siam\"?", "answer": "The King and I", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea4", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Peter, Paige and Jason?", "answer": "FoxTrot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c5", "question": "What island is Tokyo located on?", "answer": "Honshu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f1684df7c52aae91cc07c5", "question": "Selaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Light flashes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc3ae6ce05a3942286f26", "question": "John Paul Jones was the bassist and keyboardist for what rock band?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9a", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Air Force One\"?", "answer": "Harrison Ford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cbe", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Stonecutters\" fraternity?", "answer": "The Simpsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbd535000d154d7af00b8dc", "question": "Which band recorded and released the song\"Cotton Eye Joe\"?", "answer": "Rednex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc842a078d18506ae1fe48d", "question": "Who was the front for the British band \"Culture Club\"?", "answer": "Boy George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e07afe83fe1f2a824b8d", "question": "Which Old West figure became sports editor for the \"New York Morning Telegraph?\"", "answer": "William Barclay \"Bat\" Masterson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d2", "question": "In the TV show \"Knight Rider\", what does K.I.T.T.'s name stand for?", "answer": "Knight Industries Two Thousand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d8", "question": "What island is the largest of the Canary islands?", "answer": "Tenerife", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdaba4a0b8cce1e6fda7057", "question": "What cheese's name literally means \"recooked\" in Italian?", "answer": "Ricotta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049ca0cf93664eb10486a8", "question": "Which famous rapper died on Friday, September 13, 1996?", "answer": "Tupac Shakur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e661fe83fe1f2a824bcc", "question": "Which king preceded Queen Victoria?", "answer": "King William IV (who was Victoria\u2019s uncle)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133912e", "question": "Princess Aura is a character from which classic American comic strip?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a7", "question": "In what year did the San Francisco 49ers become the first five-time Super Bowl champs?", "answer": "1995", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad6", "question": "Dustin Hoffman earned his first Oscar nomination for what movie?", "answer": "The Graduate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b57c", "question": "What is SoHo short for?", "answer": "South of Houston or South of Hollywood", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f4", "question": "What metal item on the end of a kite string gave off the sparks in Benjamin Franklin's 1752 experiment?", "answer": "A key", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a87", "question": "What author wrote \"The Murders in the Rue Morgue\" short story?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c8", "question": "What year did Pinocchio first appear in published media?", "answer": "1883", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f3d601dd7bf43be5e818", "question": "OSHA stands for what in the US?", "answer": "Occupational Safety and Health Administration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa60", "question": "What two countries share Lake Geneva?", "answer": "France and Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2f4", "question": "Who directed the 1966 film \"Fantastic Voyage\"?", "answer": "Richard Fleischer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b933", "question": "What meal-in-a-box is called the San Francisco treat?", "answer": "Rice-a-Roni", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58bb3542e368446ca7bd6850", "question": "Which popular method of brewing coffee requires the beans to be ground to a powder?", "answer": "Turkish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a675", "question": "Richmond is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a878", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Carnaby Street\"?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c8bbfbde8045e48466df", "question": "Around 280 million years ago, the continents existed as one landmass called what?", "answer": "Pangea", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a66e", "question": "What river do the Holland Tunnel and Lincoln Tunnel pass beneath?", "answer": "Hudson River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3b", "question": "What is actor Anthony Hopkins nationality by birth?", "answer": "Welsh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93fe6ce05a3942286e93", "question": "What show did \"TV Guide\" name the \"best TV show of all time\" in 2002?", "answer": "\"Seinfeld\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339422", "question": "Who played the role of Jade in the 2009 movie \"The Hangover\"?", "answer": "Heather Graham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e96ee7ccba3ffe45786f4", "question": "A 8 to 12 mph wind on the Beaufort scale is called what?", "answer": "Gentle breeze", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d1", "question": "Which author built a home called Goldeneye in Jamaica?", "answer": "Ian Fleming", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde4a70c6c6b019850c9a75", "question": "Queen Alexandra's father and brother were kings of what country?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a13b", "question": "Which TV detective kept a pet alligator?", "answer": "Sonny Crockett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c77d03224f0f7a362efd551", "question": "Who released an album called \"Don't Shoot Me I'm Only the Piano Player\" in 1973?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b5be01dd7bf43be5e7d4", "question": "What snack was invented by monks?", "answer": "Pretzels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25f", "question": "What is a somnambulist?", "answer": "A sleepwalker", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9dc", "question": "On which island will you find \"Adams Peak\"?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c0", "question": "As what type of beans are chickpeas also known as?", "answer": "Garbanzo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339463", "question": "Who played Butch Cassidy?", "answer": "Paul Newman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6003952057a0e35c43f83892", "question": "Any color plus black is called what?", "answer": "A shade", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3cd", "question": "What is added to white sugar to make brown sugar?", "answer": "molasses", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da2", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Brown?", "answer": "Thomas Hughes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a74e", "question": "What city, located in the Sonoran desert, was once called Arizona City?", "answer": "Yuma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da9", "question": "Plato's \"Apology\" consists of what man's defence against a capital charge?", "answer": "Socrates'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b32341abf195a31e15d73a2", "question": "What desert covers most of southern Mongolia?", "answer": "The Gobi desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fe0", "question": "What was the name of Juliet's cousin killed by Benvolio in \"Romeo and Juliet\"?", "answer": "Tybalt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b54c", "question": "What two colours make purple?", "answer": "Red and Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ce", "question": "Who wrote \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Neil Gaiman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a896", "question": "What city is home to the Milad Tower?", "answer": "Tehran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4fe", "question": "What is the first foreign country you would reach if you go south of Detroit, Michigan?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81a", "question": "What is the nickname of the Great Bell at the Palace of Westminster?", "answer": "Big Ben", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef8", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Isabel Archer?", "answer": "The Portrait of a Lady", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebe", "question": "Whose series of thirteen children's books of thirteen chapters each ended in 2006 with \"The End\"?", "answer": "Lemony Snicket's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067b5dff9c0647b50a8063", "question": "On what date did singer, songwriter and actor, David Bowie die", "answer": "January 10, 2016", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc03", "question": "Who invented the correction fluid known as Liquid Paper?", "answer": "Bette Nesmith Graham", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd7e", "question": "According to the Bible, who died at the ripe old age of 930?", "answer": "Adam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a386", "question": "What is the capital of Egypt?", "answer": "Cairo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bd05cb540191c55fd523fb5", "question": "What video game, that peaked in the late 2000's, got people to try stumping a cartoon genie?", "answer": "Akinator", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab8", "question": "Which Biblical character wrestled an angel in Genesis 32?", "answer": "Jacob", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a54", "question": "What university presents the annual Pulitzer Prize journalism awards?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a77d", "question": "Which two countries border the Dead Sea?", "answer": "Israel and Jordan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ce", "question": "In a P2P network, what does the \"P\" stand for?", "answer": "Peer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59db78b50ab2c8f322317ff6", "question": "What was the name of Nazi Germany's secret police?", "answer": "Gestapo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd822e5d0de9af39e9d46ac", "question": "How many vice presidents did FDR have during his time in office?", "answer": "3", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a128", "question": "What band got their name from the 1960's film \"Barbarella\"?", "answer": "Duran Duran", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b17445bbb2d29f81593b6fa", "question": "Who wrote and starred in the 1922 version of the film \"Robin Hood\"?", "answer": "Douglas Fairbanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002405e4be4723ccac22164", "question": "Jack Ryan is the name of the CIA analyst in author Tom Clancy's novels.  What is Jack's birth name?", "answer": "John Patrick Ryan, Sr.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99c", "question": "What is the more common name for the star cluster, Pleiades?", "answer": "Seven Sisters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5b126ce05a3942286e11", "question": "Which former NBA player went by the moniker Chocolate Thunder?", "answer": "Darryl Dawkins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60121b0b63c99d48cd169b0a", "question": "The word \"susurrus\" is an example of which literary device?", "answer": "Onomatopoeia -- Some words sound just like their meanings.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c790", "question": "What color is the octopus blood?", "answer": "Light blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e87f06d333868d34d749", "question": "What US state was the first to require license plates?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067f79ff9c0647b50a8085", "question": "On what date did the 2016 Dyn Cyberattack take place, rendering some of the largest Internet services unusable for several hours?", "answer": "October 21, 2016", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339049", "question": "Who composed \"The Dream of Gerontius\"?", "answer": "Edward Elgar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae6", "question": "How many strikes in a row earns you a perfect game in regular 10\u00ad pin bowling?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c13a", "question": "How many squares are there on a chessboard?", "answer": "64", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d9abc08b8581f80b092bf", "question": "What big budget game was the subject of monetization controversy and government interference in the fall of 2017?", "answer": "Star Wars Battlefront II", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc7df6de0eb824d4052fa", "question": "What island changes hands between France and Spain every six months?", "answer": "Pheasant Island -- The two-acre island lies in the Bidasoa River between France and Spain.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c953", "question": "What is the meaning of the name of the constellation Draco?", "answer": "Dragon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339174", "question": "Who played Princess Leia in the original Star Wars movies?", "answer": "Carrie Fisher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ca", "question": "In what US state was Abraham Lincoln born?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5c8e6ce05a3942286e22", "question": "Who was Sports Illustrated\u2019s first female sportsperson of the year?", "answer": "Billie Jean King", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339517", "question": "Who was the actress murdered while taking a shower in the 1960 movie \"Psycho\"?", "answer": "Janet Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a1", "question": "Which band comprises sisters Andrea, Sharon, and Caroline with their brother Jim?", "answer": "The Corrs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b960", "question": "Excluding the Umpires, how many players take part at the same time in a game of cricket?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3a", "question": "Which basketball superstar had a major role in the 1996 movie \"Space Jam\"?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d6", "question": "What gate does the three-headed dog Cerberus guard?", "answer": "The gates to the Underworld", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fb088ebcf631c2414a13b5d", "question": "In \"Game of Thrones\", what is the language of the White Walkers?", "answer": "Skroth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397de", "question": "Which actor had to swim for his life whilst filming The Beach in 1999?", "answer": "Leonardo Di Caprio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a503", "question": "Which country has more volcanoes than any other?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974d", "question": "What is Alecia Moore better known as?", "answer": "P!NK", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a526", "question": "What are the five Great Lakes?", "answer": "Superior, Michigan, Huron, Erie and Ontario", "category": "geography"}]